Personal Information

Country: Argentina

Date of birth: Dec 12nd, 1986

Contact

E-mail: carloscgentile@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/carloscabrera011 github.com/CarlosCabreraGentile github.com/carloscgen

Acknowledges & Skills

HTML/CSS

React

Angular

Redux

Next.js

JavaScript

Node.js

Express.js

REST Services

GraphQL

Mongo DB

MySQL/PostgreSQL

Languages

Spanish (native) English B1/B2

Carlos Cabrera Gentile

Software Developer

Resume

I am a software developer, I have worked in many companies using different technologies, mainly JavaScript. I am very passionate about technology and learning new things. I like meeting new people and learning about their experiences.

Professional Experience

Longevo · Welness and Fitness

Frontend Developer Jun, 2022 - Present

Working at the back office project, for experts and coaches to manage the customer status and health. Platform developed with React and Redux with REST services and NextJS. Also with Material UI and Styled Components.

Working as a team the UX designer provides us the design or prototype made in Figma. From there I take the colors, measurements, fonts, breakpoints, images, etc.

I also give my point of view to the UX team and many times we manage to agree on certain aspects.

Blue Alba • Financial Industry

Full Stack Developer May, 2021 - Jun 2022

The application is related to financial services and investment funds, developed in Node.js with GraphQL and REST, the frontend with React/Redux and Styled Components, Postgre and Snowflake databases. The application was made with micro frontends architecture, basically 2 one microfrontend for Deals and another for Funds, I developed features for those two applications.

I have a general knowledge of that architecture.

Globant • Sistemas Globales

UI Engineer Jul, 2019 - May, 2021

-Working for Deloitte account in a large application developed with Angular 8, Less, RxJS, and .NET, fixing bugs, and managing issues and user stories.

-Working for Ernst and Young (E&Y) account.

The project was developed in React.js with Typescript and Ant Design and has an integration with PowerApps.

BeeReal · Software Development & UX Design

Full Stack Developer Jan, 2018 - Jul, 2019

I have worked with different projects for DHL, most of them with Node.js and ExpressJS at the backend with Mongo DB/MySQL depending on the project, and with Angular 8, Bootstrap, and SCSS. I was in charge of developing new features, fixing bugs, and implementing client requirements. Working with REST architecture, my daily work was based on REST APIs, from the backend designed and sent to the frontend endpoint.

Estudio DIT • Web Design

Lead Designer 2016 - 2018

Designed and developed landing websites. Developed an electronic invoice website in collaboration with a Si Factura company. Developed a demo landing page for Buenos Aires City Government.

Education

Universidad Nacional del Centro de la Provincia de Buenos Aires UX/UI Design of Digital Experiences (2019)

Universidad Nacional del Centro de la Provincia de Buenos Aires TUDAI, Computer Software Technology/Technician (2017-2019)

Universidad Nacional de Mar del Plata Industrial Designer, Product Design (2008-2012)